Raymond Nwambuonwo Software Developer

Contact

RaymondNwambuonwo@gmail.com raymondnwambuonwo.netlify.app/ Phone: 347.748.3900 Location: Washington D.C. linkedin.com/in/ravmondnwambuonwo/ github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo

Summary

education and a strong aptitude for learning and applying new concepts. From formal education to on-the-job riew concepts. From formal evolution to orther job training, I am prepared to assist software professionals in the development and modification of software and technological projects. As a former educator, I understand the importance of utilizing and conveying information the importance or utilizing and conveying information effectively. My experience as a software developer has enhanced my abilities in designing, implementing, and upgrading software. One of my primary objectives is to keep updated with the latest IT trends and technologies. I am confident that if given the opportunity, I can be a useful talent to the company.

Skills

Bootstrap CSS

HTML

JavaScript

ReactJS Material U

BACK END DEVELOPMENT

Django Express

MongoDB/Mongoose

NPM

Python

PostgreSQL

Node.JS

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES

Adobe Lightroo

Final Cut Pro X

Netlify

Agile Meth SCRUM

Full-Stack Projects

- Description: CoTripper is an application that facilitates organized group travel experiences for single-mothers. My contribution consisted of establishing an icon component library, creating the message inbox, and collaborating on the creation of the new user page. This project consisted of a team of 25 engineers where agile methodologies were used to conduct team stand-ups and
- ologies Used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, PeeWee, Storybook, & React.

Otoi | github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/Otoi

- Description: A group project consisting of 3 engineers. This application was developed as a way to keep track of important information and to have it in one central place with full CRUD function.

 Future Development: In the future, we are looking to add authentication to allow users to make profiles and login to see their specific data. We will also like to make it mobile responsive as well
- Technologies Used: MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Javascript, & React.

 $Intergalactic\ People\ |\ https://github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/StarWarsMernFrontend$

- Description: This is a MERN stack application utilizing the star wears API and developed with full CRUD allowing users to create, update, and delete a character. nents to the application, utilizing films, starships, and planets from the franchise
- Future Development: In the future, I am looking to add more components to the application, to Technologies Used: MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Javascript, & React.

Front End Projects

- Future Development: In the future, I am looking to add the option for a user to choose categories of statements they would like to type
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, & Material UI.

Typing Game | github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/Typing-Game

- Description: This is a front end application typing game that generates random statements for the user to copy and test the speed of their typing. Future Development: in the future, I am looking to add the option for a user to choose categories of statements they would like to type. Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, 5 JavaScript.

Memory Match | github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/Memory-Match

- Description: A card matching game using popular computer languages and is deployed with Netlify.
 Future Development: In the future, I am looking to add a menu and more stages with cards that incorporate more things that are associated with coding. For now, users can simply play the one stages
- Technologies Used: CSS, HTML, & JavaScript.

Tic-Tac-Toe | github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/Tic-Tac-Toe

- Description: A tic tac toe game developed in vanilla JavaScript
- Future Development: In the future, I am looking to add the computer as a component and more style options to choose from
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, & JavaScript.

- Component Library | github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/ComponentLibrary

 Description: This is a library made with storybook and it is filled with commonly used components such as buttons, dropdown menus, redeem/vouchers, and many more.

 Future Development: In the future, I am looking to add more components to choose from as this will minimize the need to rebuild things with each app.

 Technologies Used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React, & Storybook.

Back End Projects

- $Rolodex \mid github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/PythonRolodex \\ \bullet \textit{ Description}: This command-line application was developed to act as a Rolodex to store new contacts. \\$ ring to add a graphical user interface (GUI). As of now, it can be used in the command line oment: In the future, I am loo
 - Technologies Used: PeeWee, Pyscopa2, & Python.

Ping Pong | github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/PythonPongGame

- Description: This command-line application was developed as a ping pong game with a GUI.

 Future Development: In the future, I am looking to add an option to play against the computer and to choose colors of paddles and ball.

 Technologies Used: Turtle & Python.

Speech Assistant | github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/PythonSpeechAssistant

- Description: This is a speech assistant application that enables the user the say a few commands such as searching youtube, google, and storing names. Future Development in the future, I am looking to add more commands to the application. Technologies Used: GTIS, Speech Recognition, & Python.

Link Shrink | github.com/RaymondNwambuonwo/Link-Shrink

- Description: This is an application that enables the user to enter a web address and have it returned as a shortened web address.

 Future Development: In the future, I am looking to add a front end to this application.
 - Technologies Used: NodeJS, MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, ShortID, & EJS.

Experience

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive

Washington, D.C. Sept. 2019 to Dec. 2019

- Completed 500+ hours of web development training that included object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, Data Modeling, Agile Software Methodologies, and Test-Driven applications
 Utilized a hands-on approach to develop real-world applications while maintaining two GitHub profiles (Github & GH Enterprise) with a combined commit history of 400+ contributions.

University of Maryland

Largo, Maryland Aug. 2018 to Aug. 2019

- Provided excellent customer service to a diverse student population by advising on strategic planning, SMART goals, and class enrollment
- Provided excellent Customer service to a unwesse student population by southing or setting an acceptance of the service of the s

Medaille College

- Sept. 2016 to June 2018
 Supervised ten resident assistants and facilitated staff development through planning and leading weekly staff and one on one meetings and conducted low-level student conduct conversations.

 Organized staff development opportunities and participated in the hiring and training of residence life staff as to goals, objectives, university policies, procedures, professionalism, and ethics.

 Responsible for on-call duty rotation, serving as the professional staff contact responding to emergencies and crisis situations working cooperatively with Public Safety, Courseling Center and
- ugh, open houses, damage assessments, room inspections, reporting and billing, maintenance requests, hall openings and closings, emerg

Education

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive, Washington, DC

Sept. 2019 to Dec. 2019

The State University College at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY M.S. Higher Education & Student Affairs Administration

Aug. 2016 to May 2018 Aug. 2012 to May 2014

State University of New York at Oswego, Oswego, NY B.A. Broadcasting & Mass Communications

Aug. 2010 to May 2012

State University of New York at Tompkins Cortland Community College, Dryden, NY